<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="en">
	<title>OnscreenProton</title>
	<subtitle>My personal site and blog</subtitle>
	<link href="https://onscreenproton.github.io/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="https://onscreenproton.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
	<id>https://onscreenproton.github.io</id>
	<author>
		<name>OnscreenProton</name>
		<email>no@example.com</email>
	</author>
	
	<entry>
		<title>My Situation</title>
		<link href="https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2025-06-16/"/>
		<updated>2025-06-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2025-06-16/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Where am I now?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, I must apologize for going radio silent for what ended up being a year. I admittedly struggled a bit getting used to college, but it turned out that I found it easier and less time consuming than high school after a bit. I&#39;m still not sure why this is, since I didn&#39;t find high school especially hard, but I found myself with a lot of free time back then. Although, for my second semester, I took a somewhat heavy courseload and had less freetime to do other stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What have I done?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t really done too much besides school clubs since I first started. I&#39;ve honestly been really bored and constantly wished there was something more captivating to put my mind to. Hopefully that can be this blog! I don&#39;t really remember much about how I wrote this or where I stole stuff from, but I hope to have this blog serve as a small creative outlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future plans?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to learn more programming languages in addition to exploring 中文. Python for one would be quite useful to me not just for personal projects but also for school related tasks. Also, I constantly use Julia to mess around and calculate one-off things in the REPL. Maybe it would come in handy too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not super sure what the future has for me, but hopefully it is fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Rewrite of blog</title>
		<link href="https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2024-07-31/"/>
		<updated>2024-07-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2024-07-31/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I finally got this site working with eleventy and gh-pages! It was mostly not my work since I took a lot of the site from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy-base-blog&quot;&gt;the Eleventy example blog&lt;/a&gt; and from a layout from &lt;a href=&quot;https://teppyslayouts.neocities.org/&quot;&gt;teppy&lt;/a&gt;, but I put some small finishing touches on my self. Hopefully I have the motivation to continue writing here, but even if I don&#39;t, I at least know this blog is mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I decided that I wanted to reboot this blog/personal website, I knew I wanted it to be simpler and built more from the ground up. While I orignally was going to do the whole site in vanilla HTML, CSS, and JS, I decided that if I were actually using the blog, it would be worth the effort to use a static site generator. Comparing Astro, Hugo, Jekkyl, and more, I eventually decided that I would write the site using Eleventy. Eleventy seemed relatively simple to use and to move to from just HTML. This made it easier for me to use an existing &lt;a href=&quot;https://teppyslayouts.neocities.org/04&quot;&gt;layout and theme&lt;/a&gt; that I liked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it has been quite a bit since I&#39;ve written/programmed anything. I was almost dead off the water from the start. Luckily, Eleventy is quite popular and I was able to quickly learn just enough to start (although I didn&#39;t really learn much since most of this site is a copy of other&#39;s work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I started by converting the layout into different Nunjucks components. While I originally grappled with not changing the CSS and HTML and sticking with seperate &lt;code&gt;base.njk&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;header.njk&lt;/code&gt;, I folded and decided that since the navigation bar was simple enough, I would just put it within &lt;code&gt;base.njk&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I moved the actual website content from &lt;code&gt;base.njk&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;index.md&lt;/code&gt; so it would be easier for me to edit the home page of the site if I needed to. With this, I now had a somewhat working website. I still wanted to add more though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I had an existing blog, I never used it and thought that it should have a refresh while I was already working on this site. So I decided that I should also write the blog using Eleventy. This turned out to be really easy to implement since there was an existing blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/11ty/eleventy-base-blog&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; provided by the Eleventy authors. This blog fit my needs really well; it was really simple, it supports code blocks through prismjs, and seemed pretty simple to implement into my existing site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still haven&#39;t flushed out all the kinks of this setup and would like to set up a few more things. I&#39;ve been trying for a while to create a simple button in the nav bar that allows changing from dark to light mode but have not been able to figure out how to do this without changing a bunch of other things. I also would like to figure out how the image templates from the example blog work so that images are better for web use. I tried to get it to work, but relative pathes kept messing me up. Finally, I would like to rewrite the parts I took from others to be my own work. It kinda feels like I&#39;m stealing by using everyone else&#39;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re still reading this, I would like to thank you. Hopefully I&#39;ll write something else after this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OnscreenProton&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>October Update</title>
		<link href="https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2023-09-04/"/>
		<updated>2023-09-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2023-09-04/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently alive and well and have been working on upgrading on my vps setup. Over the past few months I&#39;ve found a few new pieces of software such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zadam/trilium&quot;&gt;trilium notes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/usememos/memos&quot;&gt;memos&lt;/a&gt; that seem pretty cool. I&#39;ve also set foot into the world of federated social media with new accounts on &lt;a href=&quot;https://wetdry.world/@onscreenproton&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://leathallava.land/@onscreenproton&quot;&gt;lavafish&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these seem pretty interesting and I hope to stay active on both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s pretty much it for now and I hope to have something else to put here sometime soon. I&#39;m just thinking about what else I should put here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		<title>Hello World</title>
		<link href="https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2023-06-06/"/>
		<updated>2023-06-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
		<id>https://onscreenproton.github.io/blog/2023-06-06/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a hello world post on this, I hope that this stays actively maintained by me but it probaly won&#39;t. I rebooted this for no reason other than I felt like it. I&#39;m not really sure what I&#39;ll put here, but I guess I&#39;ll find out later. As I wrote in my intro thing for this site, I don&#39;t really know a ton about programming at all, but maybe I&#39;ll have motivation to learn more if I find a project I want to work on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are going to contact me, I&#39;m not really active on any platform other than Discord, so that would be perfered.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>